A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Education and Public Policy Division, Office Files of Richard Sharpe FA557
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Future Program Planning Project, 1975-1976; III
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 5. Economic Growth -- Gordon, David M. -- "Levelling the Hills and Valleys: Moving from Uneven to Even Economic Development", Mar 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 5. Economic Growth -- Sowell, Thomas -- "'Opportunity' and 'Growth'', [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 5. Economic Growth -- Background Paper -- Bell, David and Marshall Robinson, Dec 10, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 6. Justice, Fairness -- Chalidze, Valery -- "Important Aspects of the International Defense of Human Rights", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 6. Justice, Fairness -- Cariola, Patricio, S.J. -- "A New Justice", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 6. Justice, Fairness -- Gale, Mary Ellen -- "Justice, Fairness, and Human Rights - Introduction: The Supreme Court and the Idea of Justice", Mar 1, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 6. Justice, Fairness -- Hastie, William -- Tape Recorded Remarks Re: Justice, Fairness and Human Rights, Mar 23, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 6. Justice, Fairness -- Tyler, Gus -- "A Paper on Human Rights, fairness and Justice for the Ford Foundation", Feb 5, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 6. Justice, Fairness -- Background -- Dodds, R. Harcourt and Robert H. Edwards, Dec 9, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 7. War, Peace -- Bull, Hedley -- "War, Peace and Cooperation Among Nations", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 7. War, Peace -- Nye, J.S. -- "International Conflict and Cooperation in the 1980's", Mar 1, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 7. War, Peace -- Brewer, Garry D. -- "Existing in a World of Institutionalized Danger", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 7. War, Peace -- Rubinstein, Amnon -- "A Look into the Future", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 7. War, Peace -- Background Paper -- Goodwin, Crauford D., Dec 1, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Keniston, Kenneth -- "The Nature of the Individual and His or Her Fulfillment", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Olds, James -- "The Pursuit of Happiness", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- March, James -- "The Nature of Things", 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Achebe, Chinua -- "The Nature of the Individual and His Fulfillment", Mar 11, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Huxtable, Ada Louise -- "The Individual and His Fulfillment", [1976] (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Kozol, Jonathan -- "Building a New Conception of the Nature of the Individual and of the Limits of 'Our Human Nature'", Feb 26, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Olson, David R. -- "On the Nature and Achievement of Human Competence", Mar 1, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- 8. The Individual -- Background Paper -- Saario, Terry and Basil Whiting, Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Discussion Papers -- Bundy, McGeorge -- "A Response to the Trustees on Proposed Priorities, Special Questions, and Remaining Hard Choices", Nov 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Achebe, Chinua, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Amsterdam, Anthony, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Bell, Joel, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Ben-David, Joseph, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Berelson, Bernard, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Brewer, Garry D., 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Buchan, Hon. Alastair Francis, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Bull, Hedley, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Calabresi, Guido, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Cardoso, Fernando Henrique, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Cariola, Patricio, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Chalidze, Valery, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Edelman, Marian Wright (incl. cassette tape), 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Gale, Mary Ellen, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Geertz, Clifford and Hirschman, Albert (incl. cassette tapes), 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Gordon, David, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Gordon, Kermit, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Gray, Hannah, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Habte, Aklilu, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Hamilton, Charles, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Haq, Mahbub ul, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Haskins, Caryl P., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Hastie, Willliam H. (incl. cassette tapes), 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Huntington, Samuel P., 1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Huxtable, Ada Louise, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Islam, Nurul, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Johnson, Harry G., 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Kaplan, Martin, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Keniston, Kenneth, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Kothari, Rajni, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Kozol, Jonathan, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Legesse, Asmarom, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Levitan, Sar A., et al., 1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- March, James, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Merton, Robert, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Miller, William Lee, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Nozick, Robert, 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Consultant Files -- Nye, Joseph F., Jr., 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Future Program Planning Project -- Other Consultant Appointments, 1976 (Box 10)
- Reports, Conferences, Papers, Reprints, 1977-1981; IV
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "A Portfolio of Large-Scale Possibilities" (1 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "An Attempt at Self-Management on the Reservations" (2 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "The Ford Foundation Management and Program Trends in the Fifties and Sixties" (3 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "PAYE: Final Recommendations" (4 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "PAYE: A Report to the Trustees" (5 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "Report of the Internal Foundation Conference on Ford Foundation Programs in Europe" (2/24-25/1971) (6 of 9), Jul 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "Proposed Budget, FY 1972" (7 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "Toward a Revised Program Emphasis for the Division of Education and Research of the Ford Foundation" (8 of 9), Sep 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXVI (June-July 1971) -- "Pay as You Earn - Staff Papers on Income Contingent Lending" (9 of 9), Jun 1971 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXXI (April-May 1972) -- Library Handbook (1 of 6), Apr 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXXI (April-May 1972) -- "Social Considerations and the Investment Process" by Bevis Longstreth and H. David Rosenbloom (2 of 6), Apr 15, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXXI (April-May 1972) -- "Can Leadership Be Learned? An Assessment of the Work of the National Fellows Program" (3 of 6), Apr 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXXI (April-May 1972) -- "The Students Deserve Better" (4 of 6), Apr 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXXI (April-May 1972) -- "Two Organizations, Two Approaches, One Objective" Re: Grants to Capital Formation Inc. and Chicago Economic Development Corp. (5 of 6), Apr 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Planning Papers, Book XXXI (April-May 1972) -- "The Foundation and the Less Developed Countries - The Decade of the Seventies", Apr 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Education and Development Reconsidered - Vol. One" -- Prepared for the Conference at Villa Serbelloni, Bellagio, Italy, May 3-5, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Education and Development Reconsidered - Vol. Two" -- Prepared for the Conference at Villa Serbelloni, Bellagio, Italy, May 3-5, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "The Equal Rights Amendment: A Discussion", May 22, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "International Research and Exchange Board", Dec 1972 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Little Cooperation on Co-ops", Apr 1973 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "The Ford Foundation and Public Broadcasting", Jul 10, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Report of the Subcommittee on Education of the Telecommunications Task Force", Jul 1973 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Employment in Developing Countries" by Edgar O. Edwards, Aug 1973 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Education and Development - Agenda Papers" Prepared for Conference at Villa Serbelloni, Bellagio, Italy, Nov 1-9, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Problems and Issues Concerning Vietnam Veterans, Deserters, and Draft-Evaders", Sep 1974 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Choices Under a Reduced Program Budget", Nov 1974 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "The Ford Foundation's Program in School Staff Development" and Additional Reports, Speeches Re: Public Education, by Edward Meade and Dick Lacey; Grants, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Reports Re: Educational Research by Robert G. Myers, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Report of the Mission on Basic Education to Agencies Participating in the Bellagio Education Meetings" by Richard S. Sharpe and Jinapala Alles, Mar 1975 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Capacity Building in Planning and Research" for Meeting on Assistance to Education (Sep 16-18, 1975) by David Bell, Sep 18, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Education Research - The Promise and the Problem" by Harold Howe II, Apr 21, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Implementation of the Agrarian and Educational Reforms in Peru" Prepared for Conference in Texas (Apr 29-May 1, 1976) by Peter S. Cleaves (Box 10)
  - Reports -- Bellagio Papers Re: Educational Research and Development, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- "Federal Agencies and Urban Segregation - Steps Toward Coordinated Action" by Gary Orfield, Aug 1978 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- PIACT Papers, "Evaluation of the Safety of Modern Contraceptives in Developing Countries" by Olivia Schieffelin Nordberg and Linda E. Atkinson, Jan 1979 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- International Division Conference (Mar 21-24, 1979) -- Papers Re: Division Management, Programs, and Geographic Spread (Box 10)
  - Reports (research funded by Ford Foundation) -- "La Reproduccion y el Bienestar Humano: Un Desafio a la Investigacion", Jun 1977 (Box 10)
  - Reports (research funded by Ford Foundation) -- Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation -- Summary, Findings and Recommendations from National Supported Work Demonstration, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Reports (research funded by Ford Foundation) -- "A Directory of Selected Women's Research and Policy Centers", Jul 1981 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Reprints -- "Foundations and Public-Private Ventures" by Franklin Thomas, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Reprints -- "Minorities and Housing: Are the Doors Really Open?" by Robert Chandler, Jul/Aug 1979 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Reprints -- "A Tale of Three Cities: Boston, Birmingham, Hartford", 1981 (Box 10)
  - Ford Foundation Reprints -- "Minorities and Mathematics", Aug 1981 (Box 10)
- Education, Social Sciences and Public Policy Programming Files, 1960-1981; V
  - A&P -- Grant Evaluation -- Pilot Project in Educational Television in the Philippines, 1971-1975 (Box 11)
  - International Division -- Grant Closures and Grant Lists; Report, "Grant Monitoring and Project Evaluation" by Curt Wolters, 1974 (Box 11)
  - International Division -- "Field Office Program Development Strategies in Education: Action vs. Research" by Richard S. Sharpe, n.d. (Box 11)
  - International Division -- Management and Operations -- Memoranda Re: Grant Actions, Budget Process, Programming, etc., 1971-1976 (Box 11)
  - International Educational Development -- Memoranda, 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Intergovernmental Conference on Cultural Policies in Africa -- Unesco Conference (Accra, Oct 27-Nov 6, 1975) -- General Information, papers, etc. (Box 11)
  - Intergovernmental Conference on Communication Policies in Latin America and the Caribbean -- Unesco Conference (Costa Rica, July 12-21, 1976), Jul 1976 (Box 11)
  - African Education and Ford Foundation Programming, 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - Conference of Ministers of Education of African Member States (Jan 27-Feb 4, 1976) -- Memoranda, Reports (1 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Conference of Ministers of Education of African Member States (Jan 27-Feb 4, 1976) -- Memoranda, Reports (2 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Ghana -- Accra Office -- Quarterly Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- West Africa Regional Office -- Annual Report, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- West Africa Regional Office -- Annual Report, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- West Africa Regional Office -- Annual Report, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- West Africa Regional Office -- Quarterly Reports and Memoranda, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- Vocational Improvement Centres -- Manuals Prepared by Ford Foundation Seminars, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- Education -- "Report on the Supply of Secondary Level Teachers in English-Speaking Africa" (Ford Foundation funded), 1973 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- Education, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- Education -- "Investment in Education" Report (background information), 1960 (Box 11)
  - Nigeria -- Education -- Public Service Review Commission, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Governmental Population Policies in West Africa" by Davidson R. Gwatkin, Dec 1970 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Ghana and the Ford Foundation in the 1960s and 1970s" by David R. Smock, Feb 1971 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Studies in National Unity in West African Countries" by David R. Smock, Feb 1971 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Evaluation of the Northern Nigeria Teacher Education Project (640-0451 and 640-0451A) by Ross E. Bigelow, Feb 15, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Libraries in Nigeria" by Philip Rappaport for Ford Foundation Seminar (March 15-17, 1971), Mar 1971 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Staff Development at Four West African Universities"/"An Evaluation of Ford Foundation Staff Development Grants" by John J. Stremlau and Carolyn C. Stremlau, Dec 1973 (Box 11)
  - Reports -- "Report on the Conference of Ministers of Education of African States" by Melvin J. Fox, Mar 16, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Reports Re: Education, Development and Manpower Programs in Africa (not Ford Foundation reports), 1966-1974 (Box 11)
  - Reports Re: West African Education and University Programs and Plans, and Ford Foundation West Africa Regional Office 1973 Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Nairobi Office Budget Projections, May 1981 (Box 11)
  - Nairobi Office/Eastern and Southern Africa Programs and Studies Re: Population, Health, Nutrition (1 of 2), 1977-1981 (Box 11)
  - Nairobi Office/Eastern and Southern Africa Programs and Studies Re: Population, Health, Nutrition (2 of 2), 1977-1981 (Box 12)
  - Nairobi -- "Population Studies and Research Institute - University of Nairobi - The First Four Years" by John F. Kantner and Ozzie G. Simmons, Jun 1981 (Box 12)
  - Report on Trip to Pakistan Re: Study of Women's Educational Opportunities and Social Roles by Audrey Smock (Nairobi Office), Oct 1976 (Box 12)
  - Unesco Seminar on Educational Planning and Administration (in Africa), Apr 13-18, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Educational Broadcasting Conference in Kuwait (Mar 1-5, 1975) (Box 12)
  - Tel Aviv University School of Education -- Research Proposals to Ford Foundation, Feb 1976 (Box 12)
  - Notebooks -- Mexico and Chile, 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Notebooks -- Colombia and Peru I, [1980] (Box 12)
  - Notebooks -- Kenya I, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Notebooks -- Miscellaneous (1 of 2), n.d. (Box 12)
  - Notebooks -- Miscellaneous (2 of 2), n.d. (Box 12)
  - Bill Moyers' Journal -- "The New Equality: How Much and For Whom?" WNET Public Television, Feb 29, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Reports -- "Libraries and Library Development in Nigeria" by Philip Rappaport, Dec 1971; Oversize. (Box 13)